Register of the Pathfinder Press Publications, 1922-2014
Hoover Institution Archives
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, PART I (Box 40-49)
  - Pathfinder Press English-Language Imprints, 1993-2002. (Box 41)
    - Trotsky, Leon. The Third International after Lenin. Translated by John G. Wright. Fourth edition. 380 p., 1996 (Box 42)
    - At the Side of Che Guevara: Interviews with Harry Villegas (Pombo). First edition.39 p., 1997 (Box 42)
    - Trotsky, Leon. Europe and America: Two Speeches on Imperialism. Second printing. 86 p., 1997 (Box 42)
    - Villegas, Harry. Pombo, a Man of Che's Guerrilla: With Che Guevara in Bolivia, 1966-68. Edited by Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.365 p., 1997 (Box 42)
    - Cancel Miranda, Rafael. Puerto Rico: Independence Is a Necessity. 36 p., 1998 (Box 42)
    - Kofsky, Frank. John Coltrane and the Jazz Revolution of the 1960s. Expanded and revised second edition of Black Nationalism and the Revolution in Music. 500 p., 1998 (Box 42)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice. Che Guevara and the Imperialist Reality. First edition. 33 p., 1998 (Box 42)
    - Barnes, Jack. Capitalism's World Disorder: Working-Class Politics at the Millennium. Edited by Steve Clark. Second printing. 501 p., 1999 (Box 42)
    - Kofsky, Frank. Black Music, White Business: Illuminating the History and Political Economy of Jazz. Second printing. 165 p., 1999 (Box 42)
    - Making History: Interviews with Four Generals of Cuba's Revolutionary Armed Forces. Edited by Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.1 93 p., 1999 (Box 42)
    - Barnes, Jack. The Working Class and the Transformation of Learning: The Fraud of Education Reform under Capitalism. First edition.34 p., 2000 (Box 43)
    - Guevara, Ernesto. Che Guevara Speaks. Second edition.1 88 p., 2000 (Box 43)
    - Guevara, Ernesto. Che Guevara Talks to Young People. Edited by Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.1 62 p., 2000 (Box 43)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice. Pathfinder Was Born with the October Revolution. First edition.22 p., 2000 (Box 43)
    - Barnes, Jack. Cuba and the Coming American Revolution. Edited by Steve Clark. First edition.1 07 p., 2001 (Box 43)
    - Castro, Fidel. Playa Girón: Bay of Pigs, Washington's First Military Defeat in the Americas. By Fidel Castro and José Ramón Ferná ndez; edited by Steve Clark and Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.278 p., 2001 (Box 43)
    - Roberts, Dick. Revolution in the Congo. Second edition.22 p., 2001 (Box 43)
    - Saldaña, Rodolfo. Fertile Ground: Che Guevara and Bolivia: A Firsthand Account. Edited by Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.86 p., 2001 (Box 43)
    - Barnes, Jack. Their Trotsky and Ours. Edited by Steve Clark and Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.1 51 p., 2002 (Box 43)
    - Cannon, James P. The History of American Trotskyism, 1928-1938: Report of a Participant. Fourth edition.316 p., 2002 (Box 43)
    - Diez Acosta, Tomá s. October 1962: The"Missile" Crisis as Seen from Cuba. Edited by Steve Clark and Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.333 p., 2002 (Box 43)
    - Dreke, Victor. From the Escambray to the Congo: In the Whirlwind of the Cuban Revolution. Edited by Mary-Alice Waters. First edition.1 82 p., 2002 (Box 43)
    - Sankara, Thomas. We Are Heirs of the World's Revolutions: Speeches from the Burkina Faso Revolution, 1983-87. 74 p., 2002 (Box 43)
    - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X Talks to Young People: Speeches in the United States, Britain, and Africa. Edited by Steve Clark. Second edition.1 52 p., 2002 (Box 43)
  - Education for Socialists English-Language Bulletins, 1995-2002. (Box 43)
    All published by Pathfinder Press in New York City
    - A New Probe by the Workers League against the Communist Movement. 22 + 7 p., 1995 (Box 43)
    - Background to"The Changing Face of U. S. Politics" and"U. S. Imperialism Has Lost the Cold War." 53 p., 1998 (Box 43)
    - Maoism vs. Bolshevism. 75 p., 1998 (Box 43)
    - Pathfinder Was Born with the October Revolution. 74 p., 1998 (Box 43)
    - In Defense of Revolutionary Centralism. 33 p., 1999 (Box 43)
    - 1999 Preface to"The Changing Face of U. S. Politics: Working-Class Politics and the Trade Unions." 12 p. (Box 43)
    - Lenin, V. I. Imperialism, the Highest Stage of Capitalism. 50 p., 2002 (Box 43)
  - Related English-Language Imprints, 1969-1998 (Box 44)
    - Mandel, Ernest. The Revolutionary Student Movement: Theory and Practice. New York: Young Socialist Alliance, 39 p., 1969 (Box 44)
    - New International: A Magazine of Marxist Politics and Theory. New York. No.1 0-11., 1994-1998 (Box 44)
    - Pathfinder Press Was Born with the October Revolution. New York: The Militant, 76 p., 1998 (Box 44)
  - Pathfinder Press Spanish-Language Imprints, 1988-2002. (Box 44)
    - El aborto: Derecho fundamental de la mujer. [ Abortion Is a Woman's Right! Spanish translation. ] 46 p., 1988 (Box 44)
    - Koppel, Martín. Sendero Luminoso: Evolución de una secta estalinista. [ Peru's Shining Path: Anatomy of a Reactionary Sect. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.37 p., 1994 (Box 44)
    - Craine, Naomi. Por qué sigue preso Mark Curtis? [Why Is Mark Curtis Still in Prison? Spanish translation. ] 86 p., 1995 (Box 44)
    - Trotsky, León. En defensa del marxismo: Las contradicciones sociales y politicas de la Unión Sovietica. [ In Defense of Marxism: The Social and Political Contradictions of the Soviet Union. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.356 p., 1995 (Box 44)
    - Barnes, Jack. El rostro cambiante de la política en Estados Unidos: La política obrera y los sindicatos. [ The Changing Face of U. S. Politics: Working-Class Politics and the Trade Unions. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.510 p., 1997 (Box 44)
    - Junto a Che Guevara: Entrevistas a Harry Villegas (Pombo). [ At the Side of Che Guevara: Interviews with Harry Villegas (Pombo). Spanish version. ] Primera edición.39 p., 1997 (Box 44)
    - Tablada, Carlos. Che Guevara: Economía y política en la transición al socialismo. [ Che Guevara: Economics and Politics in the Transition to Socialism. Spanish version. ] Primera edición.276 p., 1997 (Box 44)
    - Cancel Miranda, Rafael. Puerto Rico: La independencia es una necesidad. [ Puerto Rico: Independence Is a Necessity. Spanish version. ] 1998.37 p. (Box 44)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice. Che Guevara y la realidad imperialista. [ Che Guevara and the Imperialist Reality. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.35 p., 1998 (Box 44)
    - Barnes, Jack. El rostro cambiante de la política en Estados Unidos: La política obrera y los sindicatos. [ The Changing Face of U. S. Politics: Working-Class Politics and the Trade Unions. Spanish translation. ] Segunda edición.510 p., 1999 (Box 44)
    - Barnes, Jack. La clase trabajadora y la transformación de la educación: El fraude de la reforma educativa bajo el capitalismo. [ The Working Class and the Transformation of Learning: The Fraud of Educational Reform under Capitalism. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.37 p., 2000 (Box 44)
    - Guevara, Ernesto. Che Guevara habla a la juventud. [ Che Guevara Talks to Young People. Spanish version. ] Primera edición.1 70 p., 2000 (Box 44)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice. Pathfinder naciócon la Revolución de Octubre. [ Pathfinder Was Born with the October Revolution. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.23 p., 2000 (Box 44)
    - Barnes, Jack. Cuba y la revolución norteamericana que viene. [ Cuba and the Coming American Revolution. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.1 19 p., 2001 (Box 44)
    - Castro, Fidel. Playa Girón: Bahía de cochinos: Primera derrota militar de Washington en América. Fidel Castro y José Ramón Ferná ndez. [ Playa Girón: Bay of Pigs, Washington's First Military Defeat in the Americas. Spanish version. ] Primera edición.291 p., 2001 (Box 45)
    - Haciendo historia: Entrevistas con cuatro generales de las Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias de Cuba. [ Making History: Interviews with Four Generals of Cuba's Revolutionary Armed Forces. Spanish version. ] 203 p., 2001 (Box 45)
    - Sankara, Thomas. La emancipación de la mujer y la lucha africana por la libertad. [ Women's Liberation and the African Freedom Struggle. Spanish translation. ] 51 p., 2001 (Box 45)
    - Barnes, Jack. Su Trotsky el y nuestro. [ Their Trotsky and Ours. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.1 60 p., 2002 (Box 45)
    - Cannon, James P. La historia del trotskismo americano, 1928-1938: Informe de un partícipe. [ The History of American Trotskyism, 1928-1938: Report of a Participant. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.344 p., 2002 (Box 45)
    - Dreke, Victor. De la sierra del Escambray al Congo: En la vorá gine de la Revolución Cubana. [ From the Escambray to the Congo: In the Whirlwind of the Cuban Revolution. Spanish version. ] Primera edición.1 85 p., 2002 (Box 45)
    - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X habla a la juventud: Discursos en Estados Unidos, Gran Bretaña y á frica. [ Malcolm X Talks to Young People: Speeches in the United States, Britain and Africa. Spanish translation. ] Primera edición.1 61 p., 2002 (Box 45)
  - Education for Socialists Spanish-Language Bulletin, 2002 (Box 45)
    - Lenin, V. I. El imperialismo, fase superior del capitalismo. [ Imperialism, the Highest Stage of Capitalism. Spanish translation. ] New York: Pathfinder Press, 55 p., 2002 (Box 45)
  - Related Spanish-Language Imprints, 1991-2003 (Box 45)
    - Mandela, Nelson. Intensifiquemos la lucha: Dicursos en Africa, Europa y Norteamérica. [ Intensify the Struggle to Abolish Apartheid. Spanish translation. ] Premier edición venezolana. Caracas: Editorial Nueva Sociedad, 108 p., 1991 (Box 45)
    - Nueva Internacional: Una revista de política y teoria marxistas. New York. No.4-5., 1995-1999 (Box 45)
    - Che en la memoria: Entrevistas a Harry Villegas (Pombo). [ At the Side of Che Guevara: Interviews with Harry Villegas (Pombo). Spanish version. ] Havana: Editora Política, 47 p., 1998 (Box 45)
    - Guevara, Ernesto. Che Guevara habla a la juventud. [ Che Guevara Talks to Young People. Spanish version. ] Segunda edición. Havana: Casa Editora Abril, 143 p., 2001 (Box 45)
    - Saldaña, Rodolfo. Terreno fértil: Che Guevara y Bolivia: Relato testimonial. [ Fertile Ground: Che Guevara and Bolivia: A Firsthand Account. Spanish version. ] Havana: Editora Política, 82 p., 2001 (Box 45)
    - Diez Acosta, Tomá s. Octubre de 1962: A un paso del holocausto: Una mirada cubana a la crisis de los misiles. [ October 1962: The"Missile" Crisis as Seen from Cuba. Spanish version. ] Havana; Editora Política, 256 p., 2002 (Box 45)
    - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X habla a la juventud: Discursos en Estados Unidos, Gran Bretaña y á frica. [ Malcolm X Talks to Young People: Speeches in the United States, Britain and Africa. Spanish translation. ] Havana: Casa Editora Abril, 169 p., 2003 (Box 45)
    - Feldman, Fred. Los avances anticapitalistas en Vietnam. N. p.: Ediciónes Antid Oto, 65 p., n. d. (Box 45)
  - Pathfinder Press French-Language Imprints, 1995-2002. (Box 46)
    - Castro, Fidel. La deuxième déclaration de La Havane: Suivie de La première déclaration de La Havane. [ The Second Declaration of Havana: With the First Declaration of Havana. French translation. ] 1995.52 p. (Box 46)
    - Socialist Workers Party. Programme d'action pour faire face à la crise économique qui vient. [ Action Program to Confront the Coming Economic Crisis. French translation. ] 57 p., 1996 (Box 46)
    - Barnes, Jack. Le visage changeant de la politique aux états-Unis: La politique ouvrière et les syndicats. [ The Changing Face of U. S. Politics: Working-Class Politics and the Trade Unions. French translation. ] Première édition.524 p., 1997 (Box 46)
    - Barnes, Jack. La classe ouvrière et la transformation de l'éducation: L'imposture de la réforme de l'école sous le capitalisme. [ The Working Class and the Transformation of Learning: The Fraud of Educational Reform under Capitalism. French translation. ] Première édition.38 p., 2000 (Box 46)
    - Barnes, Jack. Le désordre mondial du capitalisme: La politique ouvrière au millénaire. [Capitalism's World Disorder: Working-Class Politics at the Millennium. French translation. ] Première édition.557 p., 2000 (Box 46)
    - Barnes, Jack. Cuba et la révolution américaine à venir. [ Cuba and the Coming American Revolution. French translation. ] Première édition.1 19 p., 2001 (Box 46)
    - Sankara, Thomas. L'émancipation des femmes et la lutte de libération de l'Afrique. [ Women's Liberation and the African Freedom Struggle. French version. ] Première édition.49 p., 2001 (Box 46)
    - Sankara, Thomas. Nous sommes les héritiers des révolutions du monde: Discours de la révolution au Burkina Faso, 1983-1987. [ We Are Heirs of the World's Revolutions: Speeches from the Burkina Faso Revolution, 1983-87. French version. ] 76 p., 2001 (Box 46)
    - Tablada, Carlos. Che Guevara: L'économie et la politique dans la transition au socialisme. [ Che Guevara: Economics and Politics in the Transition to Socialism. French translation. ] Deuxième édition.314 p., 2001 (Box 46)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice. Pathfinder est néavec la révolution d'Octobre. [ Pathfinder Was Born with the October Revolution. French translation. ] Première édition.25 p., 2001 (Box 46)
    - Cannon, James P. L'histoire du trotskysme américain, 1928-1938: Le rapport d'un participant. [ The History of American Trotskyism, 1928-1938: Report of a Participant. French translation. ] Première édition.350 p., 2002 (Box 46)
  - Education for Socialists French-Language Bulletin, 41 p., 1997 (Box 46)
    - La révolution socialiste et la lutte de libération des femmes [ Women's Liberation and the Socialist Revolution. French translation. ], 1997 (Box 46)
  - Related French-Language Imprints, 1976-1999 (Box 46)
    - Poulin, Richard. Le maoisme: Mythe et realité. Par Richard Poulin, Katie Curtin et David Frankel. Montreal: éditions d'Avant-Garde, 48 p., 1976 (Box 46)
    - Nouvelle Internationale: Une revue de politique et de théorie marxistes. New York. No.5-6., 1995-1999 (Box 46)
  - Italian-Language Imprints, 1970-1996 (Box 47)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice. Maoismo e potere negro. Rome: Edizioni Samonà e Savelli, 96 p., 1970 (Box 47)
    - Mandela, Nelson. Contro ogni razzismo: Discorsi in Africa, Europa e Norteamerica. [ Intensify the Struggle to Abolish Apartheid. Italian translation. ] Milan: Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 169 p., 1996 (Box 47)
    - Mandela, Nelson. Mai più schiavi! Sudafrica e Cuba nel mondo di oggi. Nelson Mandela e Fidel Castro. [ How Far We Slaves Have Come! South Africa and Cuba in Today's World. Italian translation. ] Milan: Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 124 p., 1996 (Box 47)
  - Pathfinder Press Swedish-Language Imprints, 1997-2001. (Box 47)
    - Socialist Workers Party. Handlingsprogram för att bemöta den kommande ekonomiska krisen. [ Action Program to Confront the Coming Economic Crisis. Swedish translation. ] 50 p., 1997 (Box 47)
    - Barnes, Jack. Arbetarklassen och lärandets förändring: Bluffen om utbildningsreformer under kapitalismen. [ The Working Class and the Transformation of Learning: The Fraud of Educational Reform under Capitalism. Swedish translation. ] Första utgavan.36 p., 2001 (Box 47)
  - Related Swedish-Language Imprint, 1995 (Box 47)
    - Ny International: Tidskrift för marxistisk politik och teori. New York. No.2., 1995 (Box 47)
  - Pathfinder Press Icelandic-Language Imprint, 2001 (Box 47)
    - Barnes, Jack. Verkalýdsstéttin og umbreyting ná ms: Blekking menntunarumbóta i kapitalismanum. [ The Working Class and the Transformation of Learning: The Fraud of Educational Reform under Capitalism. Icelandic translation. ] Fyrsta útgá fa. New York.35 p., 2001 (Box 47)
  - Related Icelandic-Language Imprint, 2002 (Box 47)
    - Nýtt Albjódlegt: Timarit um marxisk stjórnmá l og fraedikenningu. New York. No.1., 2002 (Box 47)
  - Turkish-Language Imprints, 1996-1997 (Box 47)
    - Tablada, Carlos. Che'de sosyalist bilinç ve geçis dönemi ekonomisi. [ Che Guevara: Economics and Politics in the Transition to Socialism. Turkish translation. ] Istanbul: Çözüm Yayincilik, 209 p., 1996 (Box 47)
    - Guevara, Ernesto. Che Guevara Konusuyor. Istanbul: Çinar Yayinlan, 200 p., 1997 (Box 47)
  - Pathfinder Press Greek-Language Imprints, 1994-2000. (Box 47)
    - Giougkoslavia: Oi rizes tes syrraxes. [ The Truth about Yugoslavia: Why Working People Should Oppose Intervention. Greek translation. ] 79 p., 1994 (Box 47)
    - Barnes, Jack. E poreia tou imperialismou pros to phasismo kai tou polemo. 174 p., 1995 (Box 47)
    - Castro, Fidel. E deutere diakeryze tes Avanas. [ The Second Declaration of Havana. Greek translation. ] 55 p., 1997 (Box 47)
    - Jenness, Doug. Oi agrotes antimetopoi me ten krise: Tes dekaetias tou 1990. [ Farmers Face the Crisis of the 1990s. Greek translation. ] 54 p., 1998 (Box 47)
    - Waters, Mary-Alice. Alo to 1848 mechri simera: O kommounismos kai o agonas gia mia laike epanastatike kyvernese. 160 p., 2000 (Box 47)
  - Education for Socialists Greek-Language Bulletin, 1998 (Box 47)
    - To metavallomeno prosopo tes politikes stis EPA. [ The Changing Face of U. S. Politics. Greek translation. ] New York: Pathfinder Press, 80 p., 1998 (Box 47)
  - Related Greek-Language Imprints, 1966-1986 (Box 47)
    - Jenness, Doug. Polemos kai epanastase sto Vietnam. [ War and Revolution in Vietnam. Greek translation. ] Athens: Neon Vivliopoaeion, 32 p., 1966 (Box 47)
    - Trotsky, Leon. Pou vadizei e Gallia, 1934-1936. [ Whither France? Greek translation. ] Athens: Protoporiake Vivliotheke, 194 p., 1977 (Box 47)
    - Trotsky, Leon. Neoi meleteiote politike. Athens: 24 p., 1986 (Box 47)
  - Pathfinder Press Persian-Language Imprints, 1994-2001. (Box 48)
    Published by Pathfinder Press in association with Talaye Porsoo Publishers, Tehran
    - Barnes, Jack. [ Washington's Assault on Iraq: Opening Guns of World War III. Persian translation. ] 221 p., 1994 (Box 48)
    - Barnes, Jack. [ Imperialism's March toward Fascism and War. Persian translation. ] 187 p., 1998 (Box 48)
    - Sankara, Thomas. [ Women's Liberation and the African Freedom Struggle. Persian translation. ] 93 p., 1998 (Box 48)
    - Mandela, Nelson. [ How Far We Slaves Have Come! South Africa and Cuba in Today's World. By Nelson Mandela and Fidel Castro. Persian translation. ] 100 p., 1999 (Box 48)
    - X, Malcolm. [ Malcolm X Talks to Young People. Persian translation. ] 153 p., 1999 (Box 48)
    - Cannon, James P. [ Socialism on Trial. Persian translation. ] 264 p., 2000 (Box 48)
    - Barnes, Jack. [ The Working Class and the Transformation of Learning: The Fraud of Educational Reform under Capitalism. Persian translation. ] 56 p., 2001 (Box 48)
    - Cancel Miranda, Rafael. [ Puerto Rico: Independence Is a Necessity. Persian translation. ] 91 p., 2001 (Box 48)
    - [ Making History: Interviews with Four Generals of Cuba's Revolutionary Armed Forces. Persian translation. ] 233 p., 2001 (Box 48)
  - Related Persian-Language Imprints, 1974-1975 (Box 48)
    - Trotsky, Leon. [ Stalinism and Bolshevism: Concerning the Historical and Theoretical Roots of the Fourth International. Persian translation. ] N. p.: Tali'eh, 29 p., 1974/1975 (Box 48)
    - Trotsky, Leon. [ The Class Nature of the Soviet State: The Workers' State and the Question of Thermidor and Bonapartism. Persian translation. ] N. p.: Tali'eh, 75 p., 1975 (Box 48)
  - Sinhalese-Language Imprint, 1951 (Box 48)
    - Cannon, James P. [ The Twenty-fifth Anniversary of the Russian Revolution. Sinhalese translation. ] Colombo: Lanka Samasamaja, 13 p., 1951 (Box 48)
  - Chinese-Language Imprints, 1996-1997 (Box 49)
    - Trotsky, Leon. [ My Life: An Attempt at an Autobiography. Chinese translation. ] Beijing: Guo ji wen hua chu ban gong si, 512 p., 1996 (Box 49)
    - Mandel, Ernest. [ From Capitalism to Socialism. Chinese translation. ] Hong Kong: Shi yue shu wu, 228 p., 1997 (Box 49)
    - Mandel, Ernest. [ Marxism and the Fourth International. Chinese translation. ] Hong Kong: Shi yue shu wu, 334 p., 1997 (Box 49)
    - Trotsky, Leon. [ Trotsky: An Anthology. Chinese translation. ] Hong Kong: Shi yue shu wu, 343 p., 1997 (Box 49)
    - Trotsky, Leon. [ Trotsky: A Study of His Thoughts. Chinese translation. ] Hong Kong: Shi yue shu wu, 2 volumes, 1997 (Box 49)
    - Trotsky, Leon. [ Documents of the Fourth International. Chinese translation. ] Hong Kong: Shi yue shu wu, 2 volumes, 1997 (Box 49)
  - Pathfinder Press Japanese-Language Imprint, 1994 (Box 49)
    - Breitman, George. [ The Assassination of Malcolm X. Japanese translation. ] 286 p. Published by Pathfinder Press in association with Tsuge Shobu, Tokyo, 1994 (Box 49)
  - Related Japanese-Language Imprint, 1965 (Box 49)
    - X, Malcolm. [Black Resistance Movements. Japanese translation. ] Matsudo: 86 p., 1965 (Box 49)
  - Audio tapes, 1988 (Box Tapes 4-5)
    Communist International. Congress (2nd: 1920: Petrograd, Russia). Workers of the World and Oppressed Peoples, Unite! Proceedings and Documents of the Second Congress, 1920. Edited by John Riddell. New York: Pathfinder Press, 19912 volumes. Two audiotapes of interview of Charles Shipman, delegate to the Second Congress of the Communist International, used in preparation of the volume
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, PART II (Box 50-52)
  - Pioneer Publishers Imprints and Related Material, 1931-1965 (Box 50)
    All imprints published in New York City.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Permanent Revolution. Translated by Max Shachtman. 1931. 157 p. (Box 50)
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Stalin School of Falsification. Translated by John G. Wright; introduction and explanatory notes by Max Shachtman. 1937. 326 p. (Box 50)
  - Cannon, James P. The History of American Trotskyism: Report of a Participant. 1944. 268 p. (Box 50)
  - Catalogs and promotional material, 1935-1965 (Box 50)
  - Merit Publishers Catalogs, 1967-1969 (Box 50)
  - Pathfinder Press English-Language Imprints and Related Material, circa 1970-2014. (Box 50)
  - Blanco, Hugo. Hugo Blanco on Chile and Peru. 1972. 15 p. (Box 50)
  - Blanco, Hugo. “Workers and Peasants to Power!”: A Revolutionary Program for Peru. 1978. 46 p. (Box 50)
  - Seigle, Larry, Farrell Dobbs and Steve Clark. 50 Years of Covert Operations in the US. 2014. 126 p. (Box 50)
  - Catalogs and promotional material, circa 1970-1992 (Box 50)
  - Pathfinder Press English-Language Publication Manuscript, 1992. (Box 50)
    “The Case of Aníbal Escalante.” Edited by Mike Taber. 1992. 167 p. Page proofs for projected documentary publication
  - Related English-Language Imprint, 1968. (Box 50)
    Che Guevara, Che Guevara Speaks: Selected Speeches and Writings. Edited by George Lavan. New York: Grove Press, 1968. 159 p.
  - Pathfinder Press Spanish-Language Imprint, 2014. (Box 50)
    Larry Seigle, Farrell Dobbs and Steve Clark. 50 años de operaciones encubiertas en EE.UU. [50 Years of Covert Operations in the US. Spanish translation.] Segunda edición. New York: 2014. 137 p.
  - Pathfinder Press Persian-Language Imprints, 1989-2014. (Box 51)
    Published in Tehran in association with Talaye Porsoo Publications unless otherwise stated
  - Guevara, Che. [ Socialism and Man in Cuba. Persian translation.] New York. 1989. 81 p. (Box 51)
  - Barnes, Jack. [ Imperialism’s March toward Fascism and War. Persian translation.] 1998. 175 p. (Box 51)
  - Sankara, Thomas. [ Women’s Liberation and the African Freedom Struggle. Persian translation.] 1998. 93 p. (Box 51)
  - Mandela, Nelson and Fidel Castro. [How Far We Slaves Have Come! Persian translation.] 1999. 100 p. (Box 51)
  - X, Malcolm. [ Malcolm X Talks to Young People. Persian translation.] 1999. 153 p. (Box 51)
  - Cannon, James P. [ Socialism on Trial. Persian translation.] 2000. 264 p. (Box 51)
  - Barnes, Jack. [ The Working Class and the Transformation of Learning. Persian translation.] 2001. 56 p. (Box 51)
  - Cancel Miranda, Rafael. [ Puerto Rico: Independence Is a Necessity. Persian translation.] 2001. 91 p. (Box 51)